[
    {
        "question": "Ðæt (<em>scip</em>) #### sceal genægled⁠ — the ship must be nailed",
        "correctAnswer": "scip",
        "explanation": "Here 'scip' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæs cyninges (<em>word</em>) #### is soþ⁠ — The king's word is truth",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation": "Here 'word' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Godes (<em>bearn</em>) #### þrowode on þære rood⁠ — God's son suffered on the cross",
        "correctAnswer": "bearn",
        "explanation": "Here 'bearn' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt (<em>wif</em>) #### wæs gehæled of ðam wite⁠ — The woman was healed of the disease",
        "correctAnswer": "wif",
        "explanation": "Here 'wif' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hira (<em>god</em>) #### syndon drycræfta lareowas⁠ — Their gods are teachers of magical arts",
        "correctAnswer": "godu",
        "explanation": "Here 'god' is the subject and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "god",
                "explanation": "Here 'god' is the subject and plural, but since 'god' has a short syllable it should take a 'u' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>scip</em>) #### Norðmanna cam on þissum dæg⁠ — The Northmen's ships came on this day",
        "correctAnswer": "scipu",
        "explanation": "Here 'scip' is the subject and plural, so since 'scip' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Gif þa (<em>word</em>) #### sind soþ⁠ — If the words are true",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation": "Here 'word' is the subject and plural, so since 'word' has a long syllable it takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Geata (<em>bearn</em>) #### ferde to him⁠ — The children of the Geats went to him ",
        "correctAnswer": "bearn",
        "explanation": "Here 'bearn' is the subject and plural, so since 'bearn' has a long syllable it takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo geofu wæs broht for ðære synne ðæs ærestan (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — The grace was brought for the sin of the first woman",
        "correctAnswer": "wifes",
        "explanation": "Here 'wif' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He wæs hiora (<em>god</em>) #### preost⁠ — He was the priest of their god",
        "correctAnswer": "godes",
        "explanation": "Here 'god' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þæs (<em>scip</em>) #### mæst geburnen⁠ — The ship's mast burned",
        "correctAnswer": "scipes",
        "explanation": "Here 'scip' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þæt þurh (<em>bearn</em>) #### gebyrd butan weres frigum, byrd eacen wearð⁠ — through the bearing of a child without a man's embrace, that bride became great",
        "correctAnswer": "bearnes",
        "explanation": "Here 'bearn' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo is sæd ærest (<em>wif</em>) #### in Norþanhymbra mægþe ðæt heo munuchade onfenge⁠ — She is said to have been one of the first women in Northumbria to have taken nun-hood",
        "correctAnswer": "wifa",
        "explanation": "Here 'wif' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "wif",
                "explanation": "Here 'wif' is in the genitive plural as she is 'one of the first', so it takes the 'a' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "On þis dæg, com þæs hæthenes (<em>god</em>) #### wigan⁠ — On that day, the warriors of the heathen gods came",
        "correctAnswer": "goda",
        "explanation": "Here 'god' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "godes",
                "explanation": "Here 'god' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending, not the singular 'es' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða het se cyning (<em>scip</em>) #### gegearcian⁠ — Then the king ordered the preparation of ships",
        "correctAnswer": "scipa",
        "explanation": "Here 'scip' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hlosna to þæs Godes (<em>word</em>) ####⁠ — Listen to the word of God",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation": "Here 'word' is in the singular accusative, and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He Noe gebletsade and his (<em>bearn</em>) ####⁠ — He blessed Noah and his child",
        "correctAnswer": "bearn",
        "explanation": "Here 'bearn' is in the singular accusative, and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He spræc to þæt (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — He spoke to the woman",
        "correctAnswer": "wif",
        "explanation": "Here 'wif' is in the singular accusative, and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða godu fram Egiptum landum beoþ fremede (<em>god</em>) #### ⁠ — The gods from Egypt are strange gods",
        "correctAnswer": "godu",
        "explanation": "Here 'god' is the direct object and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He wolde geseean helle (<em>god</em>) ####⁠ — he would visit the gods of hell",
        "correctAnswer": "godu",
        "explanation": "Here 'god' is the direct object and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt wæron þa erestan (<em>scip</em>) #### Deniscra manna the Angelcynnes land geseah⁠ — Those were the first ships of Danish men the English people's land saw",
        "correctAnswer": "scipu",
        "explanation": "Here 'scip' is the direct object and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie writon micel (<em>word</em>) #### lofa⁠ — They wrote many words of praise",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation": "Here 'word' is the direct object and plural, so since 'word' has a long syllable it takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se fæder wið-soc eall to his (<em>bearn</em>) ####⁠ — The father denied all to his child",
        "correctAnswer": "bearne",
        "explanation": "Here 'bearn' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "bearn",
                "explanation": "Here 'bearn' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending. It is 'eall' which is the direct object"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "And mon mot feohtan orwige gif he gemeteþ oðerne æt his æwum (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — And a man can fight without charge of homicide if he finds another with his lawful wife",
        "correctAnswer": "wife",
        "explanation": "Here 'wif' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo cwen geaf þa boc to þæm (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — The queen gave the book to the woman",
        "correctAnswer": "wife",
        "explanation": "Here 'wif' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "We willaþ mid þam sceattum us to þæm (<em>scip</em>) #### gangan⁠ — We wish to go to the ship with the treasure",
        "correctAnswer": "scipe",
        "explanation": "Here 'scip' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He ærist scoop eorþan for his (<em>bearn</em>) ####⁠ — He first shaped the earth for his children",
        "correctAnswer": "bearnum",
        "explanation": "Here 'bearn' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo geaf micel giefa to þæm (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — She gave many gifts to the women",
        "correctAnswer": "wifum",
        "explanation": "Here 'wif' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie bædon to hiora (<em>god</em>) ####⁠ — They prayed to their gods",
        "correctAnswer": "godum",
        "explanation": "Here 'god' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se here ferde to þæm (<em>scip</em>) ####⁠ — The army went to the ships",
        "correctAnswer": "scipum",
        "explanation": "Here 'scip' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo (<em>cwen</em>) #### ferþ to þæm beorgum⁠ — The queen goes to the mountains",
        "correctAnswer": "cwen",
        "explanation": "Here 'cwen' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wæs (<em>giefu</em>) #### Hroþgares oft geæhted⁠ — The gift of Hrothgar was often prized",
        "correctAnswer": "giefu",
        "explanation": "Here 'giefu' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo (<em>ceaster</em>) #### ne mæg beon behyd⁠ — The city cannot be hidden",
        "correctAnswer": "ceaster",
        "explanation": "Here 'ceaster' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Sceolde monig blachleor (<em>ides</em>) #### bifiende gan⁠ — Many a pale-faced lady must trembling go",
        "correctAnswer": "ides",
        "explanation": "Here 'ides' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa (<em>cwen</em>) #### wæron hatene Marsepia and Lampida⁠ — The queens were called Marsepia and Lampida",
        "correctAnswer": "cwena",
        "explanation": "Here 'cwen' is the subject and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt hie ælmihtiges (<em>giefu</em>) #### anforleten⁠ — That they might lose the almighty's gifts",
        "correctAnswer": "giefa",
        "explanation": "Here 'giefu' is the subject and plural, so it loses its 'u' takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>ceaster</em>) ####, Gleawanceaster, Cirenceaster and Baþanceaster, beoþ on ceastrum weallum beworhte⁠ — The cities, Gloucester, Cirencester and Bath, are walled towns",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastra",
        "explanation": "Here 'ceastra' is the subject and plural, so it loses its second 'e' takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>ides</em>) #### sloh ða wundenlocc þone feondsceaðan⁠ — The women slew the wavy-haired fiend",
        "correctAnswer": "idesa",
        "explanation": "Here 'ides' is the subject and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo ferde to þære (<em>cwen</em>) #### broce ond fram þære cwene broce⁠ — She went to the Queen's brook and from the Queen's brook",
        "correctAnswer": "cwene",
        "explanation": "Here 'cwen' is in the posessive singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðære (<em>ceaster</em>) #### ealdorman spræc mid þæm biscope⁠ — The city's elderman spoke with the bishop",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastre",
        "explanation": "Here 'ceaster' is in the posessive singular, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæra oðer wæs (<em>ides</em>) #### onlicnes⁠ — The other had a woman's likeness",
        "correctAnswer": "idese",
        "explanation": "Here 'ides' is in the posessive singular, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He wæs on ðara (<em>cwen</em>) #### gewealdum⁠ — He was under the power of the queens",
        "correctAnswer": "cwena",
        "explanation": "Here 'cwen' is in the posessive plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðara (<em>ceaster</em>) #### wisra menn ferde to þæm cyning⁠ — The cities wise men went to the king ",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastra",
        "explanation": "Here 'ceaster' is in the posessive plural, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðara (<em>ides</em>) #### fæder wæs sæt æt wine⁠ — The ladies father was sat at his wine",
        "correctAnswer": "idesa",
        "explanation": "Here 'ides' is in the posessive plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic wæs feaxhar (<em>cwen</em>) ####⁠ — I was a hoary-haired woman",
        "correctAnswer": "cwene",
        "explanation": "Here 'cwen' is the direct object and singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo gefylled wæs wisdomes (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — She was filled with wisdom's gift ",
        "correctAnswer": "giefe",
        "explanation": "Here 'giefu' is the direct object and singular, so it loses its 'u' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ælla and Cissa ymbsæton þa (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — Aella and Cissa beseiged the city",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastre",
        "explanation": "Here 'ceaster' is the direct object and singular, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Weras and (<em>ides</em>) #### sceolan læran Godes lufan⁠ — Men and women shall learn God's love",
        "correctAnswer": "idesa",
        "explanation": "Here 'ides' is the subject and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas læston þa (<em>cwen</em>) ####⁠ — The thanes followed the Queens",
        "correctAnswer": "cwena",
        "explanation": "Here 'cwen' is the direct object and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se Hælend ymbfor ealle þa burga ond þa (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — Jesus went around all the villages and the cities",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastra",
        "explanation": "Here 'ceaster' is the direct object and plural, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "To saulum on heofonum þu selest weorþlica (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — To the souls in heaven you will give worthy gifts",
        "correctAnswer": "giefa",
        "explanation": "Here 'giefu' is the direct object and plural, so it loses its 'u' and takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða comon ða weardas to þære (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — Then the keepers came into the city",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastre",
        "explanation": "Here 'ceaster' is an indirect object and singular, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas ferde to þære (<em>ides</em>) ####⁠ — The thanes went to the lady",
        "correctAnswer": "idese",
        "explanation": "Here 'ides' is an indirect object and singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie to ðære (<em>cwen</em>) #### agefon him⁠ — Then they gave him up to the queen",
        "correctAnswer": "cwene",
        "explanation": "Here 'cwen' is an indirect object and singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He ferde to þæm ceastre mid þæs cyninges (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — He went to the city with the king's gift ",
        "correctAnswer": "giefe",
        "explanation": "Here 'giefu' is an indirect object and singular, so it loses its 'u' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hlynn wearþ on þæm (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — A great cry arose in the cities",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastrum",
        "explanation": "Here 'ceaster' is an indirect object and plural, so it loses its second 'e' and takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He geaf þa bec to þæm (<em>ides</em>) ####⁠ — He gave the books to the ladies",
        "correctAnswer": "idesum",
        "explanation": "Here 'ides' is an indirect object and plural, so it takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas geaf begas ond feoh to þæm (<em>cwen</em>) ####⁠ — The thanes gave rings and wealth to the queens",
        "correctAnswer": "cwenum",
        "explanation": "Here 'cwen' is an indirect object and plural, so it takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðin mod trymeþ mid godcundum (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — Strengthen your mind with divine gifts",
        "correctAnswer": "giefum",
        "explanation": "Here 'giefu' is an indirect object and plural, so it takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæs <em>(biscop)</em> #### swearta stan  — The bishop’s black stone",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopes",
        "explanation": "Here 'biscop' is in the singular genitive so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "biscopa",
                "explanation": "While 'biscop' is in the genitive, it is the singular 'biscopes'. Biscopa' is the genitive plural"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se <em>(þegen)</em> #### ond þa biscops fram Readingum — The thane and the bishops from Reading",
        "correctAnswer": "þegen",
        "explanation": "Here 'þegen' is the subject so it takes the nominative singular case",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæs cyninges <em>(þegen)</em> #### ferde to þæm tune  — The king’s thanes went to the town",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnas|þegenas",
        "explanation": "Here 'þegen' is the subject and in the plural, so it takes the 'as' ending of the plural nominative",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "þegen",
                "explanation": "While not apparant in the Old English, þegen is clearly plural in the modern English trans, and so takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða <em>(cyning)</em> #### ond þa biscopas on Æscesdune — The kings and the bishops in Ashdown",
        "correctAnswer": "cyningas",
        "explanation": "Here 'cyning' is the subject and plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "cyning",
                "explanation": "'Cyning' is the singular form of the word while the above word is plural. This means the correct answer is 'cyningas'. If you're not sure whether a word is plural or singular, check the demonstrative pronoun."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Eall þara <em>(biscop)</em> #### preostas ferde to þæm halige stede mid him — All the bishops’ priests went to the holy place with them",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopa",
        "explanation": "Here 'biscop' is in the possessive plural, since there are multiple priests belong to multiple bishops, so it takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "biscopas",
                "explanation": "Biscopas is the nominative or accusative plural. The genitive plural ends in 'a', so the correct answer is 'biscopa'."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In Þæs (<i>cyning</i>) #### tune —  In the town of the king",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninges",
        "explanation": "Here 'cyning' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas þara <em>(cyning)</em> #### Ælfred and Æþelred — The thane's of the Kings' Alfred and Ethelred",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninga",
        "explanation": "Here 'cyning' is in the possessive plural so it takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se (<i>biscop</i>) #### fram þæm tune — The bishop from the town",
        "correctAnswer": "biscop",
        "explanation": "Here 'biscop' is the subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða Þegnas ond se (<i>cyning</i>) #### — The thanes and the king",
        "correctAnswer": "cyning",
        "explanation": "Here 'cyning' is subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Fram þæs (<i>þegen</i>) #### tune — From the thane’s town",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnes|þegenes",
        "explanation": "Here 'þegen' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning ond þa (<i>biscop</i>) #### —  The king and the bishops",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopas",
        "explanation": "Here 'biscop' is part of the subject and plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæs (<i>þegen</i>) #### menn — The thane’s men",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnes|þegenes",
        "explanation": "Here 'þegen' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Menn fram Þara (<i>þegen</i>) #### tunum — Men from the towns of the thanes",
        "correctAnswer": "þegna|þegena",
        "explanation": "Here 'þegen' is in the possessive plural as the men are from towns belonging to the thanes, so it takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða <em>(stan)</em> #### fram þæs þegnes tune — The stone from the thane’s town",
        "correctAnswer": "stanas",
        "explanation": "Here 'stan' is subject and is plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se (<i>stan</i>) #### ond se þegen — The stone and the thane",
        "correctAnswer": "stan",
        "explanation": "Here 'stan' is subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðara <em>(wicing)</em> #### cyning wolde þæt þa Deniscan ricsoden ofer Englalande⁠ — The king of the viking's would that the Danes ruled over England",
        "correctAnswer": "wicinga",
        "explanation": "Here 'wicing' is in the possessive plural as the subject is the king of many vikings, so 'wicing' takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða bearn þæs <em>(cyning)</em> #### beoþ wis and eaþmod⁠ — The children of the king are wise and humble",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninges",
        "explanation": "Here 'cyning' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða <em>(biscop)</em> #### geaf þone stan to þæm þegne — The bishops gave the stone to the thane",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopas",
        "explanation": "Here 'biscop' is the subject and it is plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Giet wæs se <em>(cyning)</em> #### Ælfred geong⁠ — Still, the king Alfred was young",
        "correctAnswer": "cyning",
        "explanation": "Here 'cyning' is the subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se biscop grete þone (<i>cyning</i>) #### — The bishop greets the king",
        "correctAnswer": "cyning",
        "explanation": "Here 'cyning' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'grete', so is in the singular accusative and thus takes no new ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "þa biscopas geaf þone (<i>stan</i>) #### to þæm þegne — The bishops gave the stone to the thane",
        "correctAnswer": "stan",
        "explanation": "Here 'stan' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf', so is in the singular accusative and thus takes no new ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se þegen sloh þone (<i>biscop</i>) #### in þæm tune — The thane slew the bishop in the town",
        "correctAnswer": "biscop",
        "explanation": "Here 'biscop' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'sloh', so is in the singular accusative and thus takes no new ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning ond seo cwen grete þa (<i>biscop</i>) #### — The king and the queen greet the bishops",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopas",
        "explanation": "Here 'biscop' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'grete' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning sloh þa (<i>þegen</i>) #### — The king slew the thanes",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnas|þegenas",
        "explanation": "Here 'þegen' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'sloh' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se þegen geaf þa (<i>gar</i>) #### to þæm cyninge — The thane gave the spears to the king",
        "correctAnswer": "garas",
        "explanation": "Here 'gar' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "To þæm biscop geaf se cyning þa (<i>beag</i>) #### — The king gave rings to the bishop",
        "correctAnswer": "beagas",
        "explanation": "Here 'beag' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "To þæm (<i>cyning</i>) #### se biscop geaf beag — To the king, the bishop gave a ring",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninge",
        "explanation": "Here 'cyning' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending.",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se þegen ferþ to þæm (<i>biscop</i>) #### mid wordum fram þæm cyning — The thane goes to the bishop with words from the king",
        "correctAnswer": "biscope",
        "explanation": "Here 'biscop' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferþ', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se biscop ferde fram þæm (<i>þegen</i>) #### to þæm cyning — The bishop went from the thane to the king",
        "correctAnswer": "þegne|þegene",
        "explanation": "Here 'þegen' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferde', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "On þis dæg, Æðelred cyning ferde to þæm (<i>tun</i>) #### mid broðor— On this day, King Ethelred went to the town his brother",
        "correctAnswer": "tune",
        "explanation": "Here 'tun' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferde', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning ferþ to þæm (<i>beorg</i>) #### — The king goes to the mountains",
        "correctAnswer": "beorgum",
        "explanation": "Here 'beorg' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferþ', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wærferhþ biscop ferde to þæm (<i>biscop</i>) #### in Lundene ond Wiltunscire — Bishop Warfehth went to the bishops of London and Wiltshire",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopum",
        "explanation": "Here 'biscop' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferde', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se geaf þa garas to þæm (<i>þegen</i>) #### — He gave the spears to the thanes",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnum|þegenum",
        "explanation": "Here 'þegen' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "þa biscopas came fram þæm (<i>tun</i>) #### hetum Londenum ond Readingum — The bishops came from the towns called London and Reading",
        "correctAnswer": "tunum",
        "explanation": "Here 'tun' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'came', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]